In their hands, a deck of cards was the only thing more dangerous than a gun.
Maverick is a action, adventure, comedy film directed by Richard Donner.
Bret Maverick is a gambler who would rather con someone than fight them, and needs an
additional $3k in order to enter a winner-takes-all poker game beginning in a few days.
He joins forces with a woman with a marvelous Southern
accent, and the two try and enter the game.
Bret Maverick, played by Mel Gibson.
Annabelle Bransford, played by Jodie Foster.
Marshal Zane Cooper, played by James Garner.
Joseph, played by Graham Greene.
Angel, played by Alfred Molina.
Commodore Duvall, played by James Coburn.
Maverick is a 1994 American Western comedy film directed by Richard Donner,
and starring Mel Gibson, Jodie Foster, and James Garner.
The screenplay by William Goldman, based on the 1957–1962 television series of the same name created by Roy Huggins and originally starring
Garner, stars Gibson as Bret Maverick, a card player and con artist who collects money to enter a high-stakes poker game.
He is joined in his adventure by Annabelle Bransford (Foster), another
con artist, and Marshal Zane Cooper (Garner), a lawman.
The supporting cast features Graham Greene, James Coburn, and Alfred Molina, and many cameo
appearances by Western film actors, country music stars, and other actors.
Maverick was filmed from August to December 1993.
Released theatrically by Warner Bros.
on May 20, 1994, the film was both a critical and commercial success,
grossing $183 million worldwide against a $75 million budget.
It was nominated for an Academy Award for Best Costume Design.
The film explores themes of ship, saloon, poker,
mississippi river, native american.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional.